Register of the Russia Missiia (Greece) Records, 1874-1925
Hoover Institution Archives
Russia Missiia (Greece) Records,
1874-1925
33008
Russia. Missiia (Greece)
92 manuscript boxes, 1 envelope (38.5 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, communiques, financial records, reports, and printed matter, relating to Greco-Russian relations, the Balkan War of 1912-1913, the Russian Revolution, Russian refugees, and the Russian Orthodox Church. Includes consular records from Turkey and the Balkans.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1933.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Orthodox Eastern Church, Russian; Russians in foreign countries; Balkan Peninsula; Balkan Peninsula--History--War of 1912-1913; Greece; Greece--Foreign relations--Russia; Russia.; Soviet Union; Russia--Foreign relations--Greece; Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921; Turkey
Historical Note
The Russia. Missiia (Greece) Collection documents the activities of the Russian Mission in Athens, Russian consulates, and Russian refugee organizations in Balkan countries and in Turkey from 1874 until 1925. The Russian Mission and consulates represented the Russian Imperial Government until the February Revolution of 1917 and the Russian Provisional Government thereafter. The mission and consulates continued to be considered representatives of the Russian Provisional Government even after the latter was overthrown by the Bolsheviks in October 1917. They were closed by March 1924 when Greece recognized the USSR.
Some time between 1925 and 1933, the records of the Russian Mission in Greece were apparently sent to Sergei Uget, Financial Agent and Custodian of Russian Government Property in the United States, whose responsibilities included preservation of the archives of the Russian Imperial and Provisional government agencies in this country. In 1933 Uget sent about 400 boxes of documents to the Hoover Institution. The records of the Russian Mission in Greece were a part, about 15%, of the shipment. However, the correspondence between Uget and the Hoover Institution, which was not very specific on the content of the shipment, failed to mention the records of the Russian Mission in Greece. A detailed description of the shipment contents seemed unnecessary at that time. In accordance with the agreement between the parties the documents were closed to researchers for 30 years. The whole shipment was assumed to be records of the Russian Embassy in Washington. The records of the Russian Mission in Greece were not identified and organized as a separate collection until 1984.
Structure of the Finding Aid
Records of the Russian Mission in Greece include records of the Russian Mission proper (89 boxes) and of the Agent Ministerstva torgovli i promyshlennosti (3 boxes). The materials of the latter were organized as a separate series, AGENT MINISTERSTVA TORGOVLI I PROMYSHLENNOSTI OFFICE FILE. The materials of the mission proper were divided into nine series. Five of these series, CORRESPONDENCE, FINANCIAL RECORDS, OVERSIZE FILE, MEMORABILIA, and AUDIO-VISUAL, were established on the basis of physical forms of the documents. The rest of the material was divided into four series: SUBJECT FILE; RUSSIAN CHURCH; RUSSIAN CONSULATES IN BALKAN COUNTRIES AND IN TURKEY; and RUSSIANS IN FORIEGN COUNTRIES.
Since Russian diplomats sent copies of their official correspondence to other Russian diplomatic and consular offices for information, the series CORRESPONDENCE includes some correspondence which was neither sent by nor directly addressed to the Russian Mission in Greece.
The Index provides access to all names and subjects listed in the register. All series are included. Names of Russian diplomats and officials affiliated with the Russian Mission in Greece recur frequently throughout the register. An Appendix brings all these names together in one alphabetic sequence and identifies each individual.
Russian terms and names were transliterated in accordance with the Library of Congress system even if they had been previously transliterated in the original documents differently. Greek names either remained unchanged if they had been previously transliterated into the Latin alphabet or were transliterated from the Cyrillic alphabet if they appear in the original documents in Russian.
Series Description
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1906-1924. (Boxes 1-16)
  Arranged alphabetically by form of document.
- FINANCIAL RECORDS, 1895-1924. (Boxes 17-25)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1874-1924. (Boxes 26-54)
  Clippings, communiques, correspondence, financial records, memoranda, minutes, notes, printed matter, reports, speeches, arranged alphabetically by subject.
- RUSSIAN CHURCH, 1885-1923. (Boxes 55-62)
  Clippings, correspondence, financial records, memoranda, notes, printed matter, reports, arranged alphabetically by subject.
- RUSSIAN CONSULATES IN BALKAN COUNTRIES AND IN TURKEY, 1913-1924. (Boxes 62-72)
  Clippings, correspondence, financial records, reports, arranged alphabetically by aubject.
- RUSSIANS IN FOREIGN COUNTRIES, 1915-1925. (Boxes 72-87)
  Certificates, clippings, correspondence, financial records, identifications, minutes, reports, arranged alphabetically by subject.
- AGENT MINISTERSTVA TORGOVLI I PROMYSHLENNOSTI (AGENT OF TRADE AND INDUSTRY MINISTRY) OFFICE FILE, 1919-1922. (Boxes 88-90)
  Correspondence, financial records, memoranda, reports, arranged alphabetically by subject.
- OVERSIZE FILE, 1921-1923. (Box 91)
  Account book
- MEMORABILIA. (Box 92)
  Seals
- AUDIO-VISUAL. (10.A-V)
Container List
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1906-1924
  - Cover letters (Box 1., Folder 1)
  - Letters, 1913-1924, including ones by or to Amira; Baltazzi, G.; Loucas; Elliot; Foulidou; Girs, Mikhail; Izvol'skii; Lobachev; Lutskii; Narodnyi komissariat inostrannykh del (People's Commissariat of Foreign Affairs); Neratov; Serafimov, Boris; Sergii, Archimandrite; Taube, K. (Folder 2)
  - Registers
    - 1916-1917 (Folder 3)
    - 1923 (Folder 4)
  - Reports to the Ministerstvo inostrannykh del (Ministry of Foreign Affairs) and Russian diplomatic and consular offices
    - n.d. (Folder 5)
    - 1912 (Folder 6)
    - 1913
      - January-February (Folder 7)
      - March-April (Folder 8)
      - May-June (Folder 9)
      - July-August (Box 2., Folder 1)
      - September-October (Folder 2)
      - November-December (Folder 3)
    - 1914 (Folder 4)
    - 1915
      - January-February (Folder 5)
      - March-April (Folder 6)
      - May-June (Folder 7)
      - July-September (Folder 8)
    - 1916
      - January-May (Folder 9)
      - June-August (Box 3., Folder 1)
      - September-October (Folder 2)
      - October-November (Folder 3)
    - 1917
      - February-March (Folder 4)
      - April-May (Folder 5)
      - June-July (Folder 6)
      - July-August (Box 4., Folder 1)
      - October-November (Folder 2)
    - 1918 (Folder 3)
    - 1919
      - January-August (Folder 4)
      - September-October (Folder 5)
    - 1920 (Folder 6)
    - 1921 (Folder 7)
    - 1922 (Folder 8)
    - 1923 (Folder 9)
  - Reports to the Ministerstvo inostrannykh del and Russian diplomatic and consular offices, Register of (Box 5., Folder 1)
  - Telegrams among the Ministerstvo inostrannykh del and Russian diplomatic and consular offices
    - n.d., including telegrams by or to Ikskul', Neratov, Tatishchev (Folder 2)
    - 1906, including telegrams by or to Chukhnin, Gubastov, Izvol'skii, Lamzdorf, Obolenskii, Semenovskii, Svechin, Zinov'ev (Folder 3)
    - 1907, including telegrams by or to Gubastov, Izvol'skii, Shcherbachev, Shumskoi, Tatishchev (Folder 4)
    - 1908, including telegrams by or to Alekseev, Izvol'skii, Shcherbachev (Folder 5)
    - 1909, including telegrams by or to Girs, Izvol'skii, Savinskii, Sazonov, Shcherbachev (Folder 6)
    - 1910, including telegrams by or to Girs, Izvol'skii, Sazonov, Svechin, Sverbeev, Urusov, Tatishchev (Folder 7)
    - 1911, including telegrams by or to Argiropulo, T.S., Charykov, Chemerzin, Neratov, Riussi, Sazonov, Shebunin, Sverbeev, Urusov, Tatishchev, Veretennikov (Folder 8)
    - 1912, including telegrams by or to Beliaev, Bentkovskii, Demidov, Ferkhmin, Girs, Kal', Nekliudov, Neratov, Shebeko, Shebunin, Urusov (Folder 9)
    - 1913
      - Incoming
        - Argiropulo (Folder 10)
        - Arsen'ev. See Shebeko
        - Bakhmet'ev, George (Folder 11)
        - Benkendorf (Folder 12)
        - Chaidopulos (Folder 13)
        - Etter. See Benkendorf
        - Ferkhmin (Box 6., Folder 1)
        - Gartvig (Folder 2)
        - Girs. See also Obnorskii (Folder 3)
        - Ivanitskii (Folder 4)
        - Izvol'skii (Folder 5)
        - Krupenskii (Folder 6)
        - Kudashev (Folder 7)
        - Nekliudov. See Sabler
        - Neratov. See Sazonov
        - Obnorskii (Folder 8)
        - Petriaev (Folder 9)
        - Poggenpol' (Folder 10)
        - Priklonskii (Folder 11)
        - Roschakovskii (Folder 12)
        - Sabler
          - January-June (Folder 13)
          - July-December (Folder 14)
        - Sazonov
          - January-June (Folder 15)
          - July-December (Folder 16)
        - Shebeko (Box 7., Folder 1)
        - Smirnov (Folder 2)
        - Stekhel'kunov? (Folder 3)
        - Sverbeev (Folder 4)
      - Outgoing, including telegrams to Girs, Kalmykov, Nekliudov, Neratov, Sabler, Sazonov
        - January-June (Folder 5)
        - July-December (Folder 6)
    - 1914
      - Incoming, including telegrams by Artsimovich, V.A.; Bazili, N.A.; Gartvig; Girs; Izvol'skii; Kal'; Krupenskii; Neratov; Poklevskii-Kozell, S.A.;Savinskii, A.A.; Shebeko; Shtrandman; Trubetskoi, Prince
        - August (Folder 7)
        - September-December (Folder 8)
      - Outgoing, including telegrams to Artsimovich, Girs, Kal', Klimenko, Neratov, Sazonov
        - January (Folder 9)
        - August-October (Folder 10)
        - November-December (Folder 11)
    - 1915
      - Incoming, including telegrams by or to Artsimovich; Bazili; Benkendorf; Bentkovskii; Biutsov, S.S.; Dashkov; Girs; Gul'kevich; Ivanov, N.A.; Izvol'skii; Kal'; Kalmykov; Khadzhi-Lazzaro, N.S.; Lobachev; Klimenko; Neratov; Nol'de; Obnorskii; Poklevskii-Kozell; Savinskii; Sazonov; Serafimov; Trubetskoi; Veselkin
        - January (Box 8., Folder 1)
        - February (Folder 2)
        - March (Folder 3)
        - April (Folder 4)
        - May (Folder 5)
        - June (Folder 6)
        - July (Folder 7)
        - August (Folder 8)
        - September (Folder 9)
        - October (Folder 10)
        - November (Folder 11)
        - December (Folder 12)
      - Outgoing, including telegrams to Artsimovich; Gul'kevich; Kal'; Nelidov; Neratov; Sazonov; Shilling; Smirnov; Trubetskoi
        - January (Box 9., Folder 1)
        - February (Folder 2)
        - March (Folder 3)
        - April (Folder 4)
        - May (Folder 5)
        - June (Folder 6)
        - July (Folder 7)
        - August (Folder 8)
        - September (Folder 9)
        - October (Folder 10)
        - November (Folder 11)
        - December (Box 10., Folder 1)
    - 1916
      - Incoming, including telegrams by Artamonov; Artsimovich; Bakherakht; Benkendorf; Bentkovskii; Dubiagskii; Fanderflit; Girs; Gul'kevich; Ikskul'; Islavin; Izvol'skii; Kal'; Kalmykov; Khadzhi-Lazzaro; Klimenko; Lobachev; Nekliudov; Neratov; Nol'de, Baron; Pelekhin; Poklevskii-Kozell; Pokrovskii; Sazonov; Shilling; Shtiurmer; Tatishchev; Trubetskoi, Prince; Urusov; Vorontsova-Dashkova; Zubrzhitskii
        - January (Folder 2)
        - February (Folder 3)
        - March (Folder 4)
        - April (Folder 5)
        - May (Folder 6)
        - June (Folder 7)
        - July (Folder 8)
        - August (Folder 9)
        - September (Folder 10)
        - October (Folder 11)
        - November (Folder 12)
        - December (Folder 13)
      - Outgoing, including telegrams to Artsimovich; Benkendorf; Biutsov; Ebergard; Izvol'skii; Kal'; Kalmykov; Lobachev; Lysakovskii; Nelidov; Neratov; Nikiforov; Petriaev; Pokrovskii; Sablin; Sazonov; Shilling; Shtiurmer; Tatishchev; Trubetskoi; Vinogradov
        - January (Box 11., Folder 1)
        - February (Folder 2)
        - March (Folder 3)
        - April (Folder 4)
        - May (Folder 5)
        - June (Folder 6)
        - July (Folder 7)
        - August (Folder 8)
        - September (Folder 9)
        - October (Folder 10)
        - November (Folder 11)
        - December (Box 12., Folder 1)
    - 1917, including telegrams by or to Artamonov; Bakh; Bazili; Dolivo-Dobrovol'skii; Girs; Izvol'skii; Kal'; Kalmykov; Kapnist; Khadzhi-Lazzaro; Klimenko; Kolemin; Kudashev; Lobachev; Lopukhin; Maklakov; Miliukov, Pavel; Nabokov; Neratov; Nikolaev; Nol'de; Nordman; Pelekhin; Persiani; Petriaev; Petrov; Pokrovskii; Polovtsov; Sevastopulo; Shtrandtman; Smirnov; Svechin; Tarnovskii; Tereshchenko; Tukholka; Zuev
      - Incoming
        - January (Folder 2)
        - February (Folder 3)
        - March (Folder 4)
        - April (Folder 5)
        - May (Folder 6)
        - June (Folder 7)
        - July (Folder 8)
        - August (Folder 9)
        - September (Folder 10)
        - October (Folder 11)
        - November (Folder 12)
        - December (Folder 13)
      - Outgoing
        - January (Folder 14)
        - February (Folder 15)
        - March (Folder 16)
        - April (Folder 17)
        - May (Folder 18)
        - June (Folder 19)
        - July (Box 13., Folder 1)
        - August (Folder 2)
        - September (Folder 3)
        - October (Folder 4)
        - November (Folder 5)
        - December (Folder 6)
    - 1918, including telegrams by or to Avksent'ev; Chaikovskii; Dolivo-Dobrovol'skii; Golovachev; Girs; Graillet; Islavin; Kalmykov; Klimenko; Kliuchnikov; Kotsebu; Kruglikov, Apolon; Kudashev; Lobachev; Lysakovskii; Lerkhe; Maklakov; Nabokov; Pelekhin; Persiani; Sevastopulo; Shtrandtman; Smirnov; Solov'ev; Svechin; Vologodskii, Petr; Zhukovskii; Zuev
      - Incoming
        - January (Folder 7)
        - February (Folder 8)
        - March (Folder 9)
        - April (Folder 10)
        - May (Folder 11)
        - June (Folder 12)
        - September (Folder 13)
        - October (Folder 14)
        - November (Folder 15)
        - December (Folder 16)
      - Outgoing
        - January (Folder 17)
        - February (Folder 18)
        - March (Folder 19)
        - April (Folder 20)
        - September (Box 14., Folder 1)
        - October (Folder 2)
        - November (Folder 3)
        - December (Folder 4)
    - 1919, including telegrams by or to Bazili; Beliaev; Burtsev; Etter; Girs; Khomenko; Konovalov; Lebedev; Lobachev; Maklakov; Meindorf; Nabokov; Neratov; Pelekhin; Persiani; Pustoshkin; Sazonov; Serafimov, Boris; Shtrandtman; Tatarinov; Trakhachev; Vinaver; Zhukovskii
      - Incoming
        - January (Folder 5)
        - February (Folder 6)
        - March (Folder 7)
        - April (Folder 8)
        - May (Folder 9)
        - June (Folder 10)
        - July (Folder 11)
        - August (Folder 12)
        - September (Folder 13)
        - October (Folder 14)
        - November (Folder 15)
        - December (Folder 16)
      - Outgoing
        - no month (Folder 17)
        - January (Folder 18)
        - February (Box 15., Folder 1)
        - March (Folder 2)
        - April (Folder 3)
        - May (Folder 4)
        - June (Folder 5)
        - July (Folder 6)
        - August (Folder 7)
        - September (Folder 8)
        - October (Folder 9)
        - November (Folder 10)
        - December (Folder 11)
    - 1920, including telegrams by or to Bakhmet'ev, Boris; Girs; Iakimov; Iakushev, Boris; Lobachev; Lukomskii; Maklakov; Neratov; Poklevskii; Sablin; Sazonov; Shtrandtman; Smirnov; Tolkachev; Zuev
      - Incoming
        - January-June (Folder 12)
        - July-December (Folder 13)
      - Outgoing
        - January-August (Folder 14)
        - September-December (Folder 15)
    - 1921, including telegrams by or to Girs; Lobachev; Maklakov; Neratov; Poliakov; Shtrandtman; Zuev
      - Incoming (Folder 16)
      - Outgoing (Box 16., Folder 1)
    - 1922, including telegrams by or to Girs; Glinka, G.V.; Kalmykov; Neratov; Shcherbina; Shtrandtman
      - Incoming (Folder 2)
      - Outgoing (Folder 3)
    - 1923, including telegrams by or to Belanovich; Girs; Shcherbina; Shtrandtman
      - Incoming (Folder 4)
      - Outgoing (Folder 5)
    - 1924, to Girs (Folder 6)
  - Telegrams (bound journals), 1912-1913 (Folder 7-8)
  - Telegrams, Registers of
    - 1917-1918 (Folder 9)
    - 1918-1920 (Folder 10)
- FINANCIAL RECORDS, 1895-1924
  - General
    - n.d. (Box 17., Folder 1)
    - 1895 (Folder 2)
    - 1897 (Folder 3)
    - 1904 (Folder 4)
    - 1905 (Folder 5)
    - 1906-1907 (Folder 6)
    - 1907 (Folder 7)
    - 1909 (Folder 8)
    - 1910 (Folder 9)
    - 1911-1912 (Folder 10)
    - 1912 (Folder 11)
    - 1913 (Folder 12)
    - 1914 (Folder 13)
    - 1915 (Folder 14)
    - 1915-1916 (Folder 15)
    - 1916 (Folder 16)
    - 1917 (Box 18., Folder 1-2)
    - 1918 (Folder 3)
    - 1919 (Folder 4-5)
    - 1920 (Box 19., Folder 1)
    - 1921 (Folder 2)
    - 1922 (Folder 3)
    - 1923 (Folder 4)
    - 1924 (Folder 5)
  - Account books
    - 1903-1906 (Folder 6)
    - 1907-1912 (Folder 7)
    - 1908-1911 (Box 20., Folder 1)
    - 1908-1917 (Folder 2-3)
    - 1910-1915 (Folder 4)
    - 1914-1917 (Folder 5)
    - 1916 (Box 21., Folder 1)
    - 1916-1920 (Folder 2)
    - 1917 (Folder 3)
    - 1917-1918 (Folder 4)
    - 1919 (Folder 5)
    - 1919-1920 (Folder 6)
    - 1920-1923 (Box 22., Folder 1)
    - 1921-1923 (Folder 2)
    - 1923 (Folder 3)
  - Checkbooks and checkstubs (Folder 4-6)
  - Checkbooks and checkstubs (Box 23., Folder 1)
  - Receipts (Folder 2-6)
  - Reports, including ones on assistance to Russians in foreign countries
    - 1915 (Box 24., Folder 1-2)
    - 1916 (Folder 3-4)
    - 1917 (Box 25., Folder 1-2)
    - 1918 (Folder 3)
    - 1919 (Folder 4)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1874-1924
  - General
    - n.d.
      - General (Box 26., Folder 1)
      - French, In (Folder 2)
      - Greek, In (Folder 3)
    - 1874 (Folder 4)
    - 1896 (Folder 5)
    - 1897 (Folder 6)
    - 1898 (Folder 7)
    - 1899 (Folder 8)
    - 1901 (Folder 9)
    - 1903 (Folder 10)
    - 1910 (Folder 11)
    - 1912 (Folder 12)
    - 1913 (Folder 13)
    - 1914 (Folder 14)
    - 1915
      - General (Folder 15)
      - Clipping (Folder 16)
    - 1916 (Folder 17-19)
    - 1917
      - General (Folder 20-21)
      - Clipping (Folder 22)
    - 1918 (Folder 23)
    - 1919
      - General (Folder 24)
      - French, In (Box 27., Folder 1)
      - Greek, In (Folder 2)
    - 1920
      - General (Folder 3)
      - Clippings (Folder 4)
    - 1921
      - General (Folder 5)
      - Clippings (Folder 6)
    - 1921-1922 (Folder 7)
    - 1922 (Folder 8)
    - 1922-1923 (Folder 9)
    - 1923 (Folder 10)
    - 1924 (Folder 11)
    - 1925 (Folder 12)
    - 1926 (Folder 13)
  - Albania
    - 1913
      - General (Box 28., Folder 1)
      - Printed matter (Folder 2)
    - 1916 (Folder 3)
  - Anglo-Japanese Agreement, 1902 (Folder 4)
  - Armenians
    - Pireus (Folder 5)
    - Turkey (Folder 6)
  - Atanasulos (Folder 7)
  - Austro-Hungary -- relations with Serbia (Folder 8)
  - Awards and decorations
    - 1914 (Folder 9)
    - 1915 (Folder 10)
    - 1916 (Folder 11)
    - 1917 (Folder 12)
    - 1918 (Folder 13)
    - 1919 (Folder 14)
    - 1921 (Folder 15)
    - 1922 (Folder 16)
    - 1923 (Folder 17)
  - Baikowich, Stevo (Folder 18)
  - Balkan Wars, 1912-1913
    - General
      - 1912
        - July (Folder 19)
        - August (Folder 20)
        - September (Folder 21)
        - October
          - 1-10 (Folder 22)
          - 11-31 (Folder 23)
        - November
          - 1-11 (Box 29., Folder 1)
          - 12-30 (Folder 2)
        - December (Folder 3)
      - 1913
        - January (Folder 4)
        - February (Folder 5)
        - March (Folder 6)
        - April (Folder 7)
        - May (Folder 8)
        - June (Folder 9)
        - July (Folder 10)
        - August (Folder 11)
        - September (Folder 12)
        - October (Folder 13)
        - November (Folder 14)
    - Aegean islands (Folder 15)
    - Albania (Folder 16)
    - Armenians. See Prisoners of war/Turks of Armenian descent
    - Bulgaria. See Greece
    - Contraband of war
      - General (Box 30., Folder 1)
      - Blockade
        - General (Folder 2)
        - Turkey, Of (Folder 3)
    - Greece (Folder 4)
    - London Conference, 1912-1913 (Folder 5)
    - Naval operations (Folder 6)
    - Poincare, Raymond (Folder 7)
    - Prisoners of war
      - Bulgarians. See SUBJECT FILE/Balkan wars, 1912-1913/Greece
      - Turks of Armenian descent (Folder 8)
    - Red Cross societies. See Relief of sick and wounded
    - Relief of sick and wounded (Folder 9)
    - Romania (Folder 10)
    - Russia. See USSR
    - Thessalonike (Folder 11)
    - Turkey
      - Debts of (Folder 12)
      - Greeks in (Folder 13)
      - Military desertion. See Greeks
    - USSR. See also Turkey/Greeks in
      - Obnorskii, "Rossiia i balkanskii vopros (Russia and the Balkan question)." Memorandum (Folder 14)
      - Sazonov? Telegrams (Folder 15)
  - Baltic states, 1922 (Folder 16)
  - Bulgaria. See also Atanasulos
    - General (Folder 17)
    - Anarchism. See Left wing movements
    - Left wing movements (Folder 18)
  - Building of the Russian mission
    - General (Folder 19)
    - Linoleum (Folder 20)
  - Chkheidze, Mikhail (Folder 21)
  - Cipher and telegraph codes (Folder 22)
  - Colby, Bainbridge, Note of August 1920 (Box 31., Folder 1)
  - Commerce
    - n.d. (Folder 2)
    - 1914 (Folder 3)
    - 1915 (Folder 4)
    - 1916
      - General (Folder 5)
      - Greco-Russian Chamber of Commerce
        - General (Folder 6)
        - Demidov, Elim. Speech
          - Clipping (Folder 7)
          - Mimeographed copies
            - French, In (Folder 8)
            - Russian, In (Folder 9)
        - Greek press on
          - Greek originals (Folder 10)
          - French translations (Folder 11)
        - Holzinger, M. (Folder 12)
        - Michalacopoulos, M. (Folder 13)
        - Participants of the opening ceremony (Folder 14)
      - Greece -- export and import controls (Folder 15)
    - 1917
      - General (Folder 16)
      - USSR
        - Arkhangelsk (Folder 17)
        - Export controls (Folder 18)
        - Import controls (Folder 19)
        - Vladivostok. See Arkhangelsk
    - 1918 (Folder 20)
    - 1919
      - General
        - January-September (Folder 21)
        - October-December (Box 32., Folder 1)
      - Agent Ministerstva torgovli i promyshlennosti (Agent of Trade and Industry Ministry) (Folder 2)
      - Pireus (Folder 3)
    - 1920 (Folder 4)
    - 1921 (Folder 5)
  - Discoveries in Arctic region (Folder 6)
  - Estonia. See Baltic states
  - Extradition (Folder 7)
  - La Famine (Folder 8)
  - Gadzhemukov family
    - n.d. (Folder 9)
    - 1875 (Folder 10)
    - 1885 (Folder 11)
    - 1894 (Folder 12)
    - 1897. See 1910
    - 1904 (Folder 13)
    - 1905 (Folder 14)
    - 1906 (Folder 15)